SlidePlayer Privacy Policy
==========================

Last Updated: January 15, 2024

1\. Introduction
----------------

We strongly respect your privacy. This Privacy Notice details important information regarding the use and disclosure of User information collected on the Slideplayer.com website. Slideplayer.com (also referred to as Us) provides this Privacy Notice to help you make an informed decision about whether to use or continue using Slideplayer.com. Slideplayer.com reserves the right to amend the privacy policy at any time. In case of such an amendment, Slideplayer.com shall publish a relevant notification of such changes on the official Web-Site. To continue usage of the Slideplayer.com’s services, You will be asked to fill the consent application.

Slideplayer.com shall gather Personal information only in scope, that is required for providing You with relevant services and that confirms with purposes of such collection.

Slideplayer.com shall gather Personal information only for purposes, that are stipulated in this Privacy Policy, or requirements, that follow from applicable law.

We don’t process Your Personal Information longer than it is required by applicable law.

We do not transfer Your Personal Data to third parties, except cases that are mentioned in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Notice is incorporated into and is subject to the Slideplayer.com Terms of Use. Your use of the Slideplayer.com website and any personal information you provide on Slideplayer.com remains subject to the terms of this Privacy Notice and our Terms of Use.

Administrator — administrator is simultaneously a controller, a processor how these terms are understood in the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union ("GDPR"). The administration independently organizes and (or) carries out the processing of personal data, as well as determines the purposes of processing personal data, the composition of personal data to be processed, actions (operations) performed with personal data.

2\. Personal Information
------------------------

We will not give, sell or rent your email address, or any other personal information to third parties at time for any reason without Your prior consent or request for it. Slideplayer.com reserves the right to transfer your personal data to third parties only under the official request of competent state bodies, Law enforcement, government officials, or other third parties when Slideplayer.com is compelled to do so by a subpoena, court order, or similar legal procedure; or under other obligatory provisions stipulated in applicable law.

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Site, services, features and content, to administer User accounts (**Accounts**) (together, the **Service**) and to enable Visitors to enjoy and easily navigate the Slideplayer.com.

It is prohibited to use the Service for slides containing special categories of personal data and personal data relating to criminal convictions and offences.

Considering the fact that PI includes all information that can anyway conduce Your identification, we gather next categories of PI about You:

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Personal Data and Category** | **When We collect it** | **How We use it** | **Why We use it** |
| login,  <br>password (Identifiers) | In the registration procedure | We use Your personal and contact information to register You as a User and identify You in Our Services. | Necessary for the performance of a contract with you |
| Name, Surname (Identifiers) | In the registration procedure | We use this to indicate Your authorship | Necessary for the performance of a contract with you |
| Email (Identifiers) | In the registration procedure | Use email to restore and activate Your account. We use it to notify You about changes to Our Terms or Privacy Policy; to communicate with you, to send you information about your transactions. | Necessary for the performance of a contract with you |
| Social network (Identifiers): social network URL, name, surname, email | In the registration procedure | We use Your personal and contact information to register You as a User and identify You in Our Services. | Necessary for the performance of a contract with you |
| Your posts and documents | When you use our Services | It is public information, we use it to provide our service | Necessary for the performance of a contract with you |
| Ip, browser language, browser settings, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform type, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time of your request, User-agent | When you use our Services | We use it to optimize Our service and to improve Our Website, services | Necessary for Our legitimate interests |
| ToS/PP acceptance date | In the registration/new ToS/PP acceptance procedures | to understand how often we should inform and update agreement with you | Necessary for the performance of a contract with you |
| The IP address | When you use our Services | We use it to fight malicious activities and comply with local legislation | Necessary for legal obligation |
| Text messages | When You use our Feedback form | We use it to respond to your request | Necessary for the performance of a contract with you |

In particular, we have collected, sold and shared the following categories of personal information from consumers within the last twelve (12) months:

Over the past 12 months, we have not transmitted or sold personal information about you to anyone.

Moreover, we collect and store information about presentations posted by You. Such information is deemed to be public since it has been posted. We also gather information regarding messages that You send us.

We bear no responsibility for re-publishing of previously deleted materials (presentations) by other Users as during first publishing they (materials) became public.

3\. Personal Data processing purposes
-------------------------------------

We use your Personal Information only:

* to provide the Services,
* to administer your inquiries and requests,
* maintaining of the statistics,
* for the improvement of our Web-site,
* for personalization of content, that is proposed to You.

You can decide not to submit personal information, in which case we won't be able to make the Slideplayer.com services available to you.

4\. Your rights
---------------

### Under the GDPR you, as a data subject, have certain rights over the personal data that We hold and process.

At Slideplayer.com, We are committed to making it easy for You to exercise these rights in the most transparent manner possible. You can exercise any of Your rights in relation to the data that Slideplayer.com holds about you, by contacting Our data protection officer through the email address provided at the end of this section or through Your personal user cabinet.

The following are the specific rights You have over Your personal data We hold and process, namely:

1. **The right to be informed** about Our collection and processing of Your personal data including without limitation the legal basis for the collection and processing, the categories of data, the methods of data use, the envisaged period for which the personal data will be retained. This Privacy Policy should tell You everything You need to know, but You can always contact Us to find out more or to ask any questions.
2. **The right to access** Your personal data We collect about you, commonly referred to as “**Subject Access Requests**”, which provides you, as the data subject, the right to obtain a copy of Your personal data that We are processing for You
    
    Pursuant to GDPR We are required to respond without undue delay to all Subject Access Requests in practice this means We have to respond within 1 month of receipt of the Subject Access Request.
    
    Ordinarily Subject Access Requests are free of charge.
    
    We may extend the time period for responding to a Subject Access Request by a further two months and may charge a reasonable fee if We deem the request to be manifestly unfounded or excessive, however, We are required to advise You of Our intention to do this within 1 month of Your subject access request.
    
    Should You wish to make a Subject Access Request this can be done by contacting the Company using the contact details in Section 9.
    
3. **The right to have Your personal data rectified** if any of Your personal data that We collect and the process is in any way inaccurate or incomplete.
4. **The right of erasure (otherwise known as “the right to be forgotten”)**, i.e. the right to ask Us to delete or otherwise dispose of any of Your personal data that We process. Please note that this is not an absolute right and We may not be able to comply with Your request as We may be legally obliged to continue to retain Your personal data for a specific period
5. **The right to restrict** (i.e. prevent) the processing of Your personal data by us.
6. **The right to object** to Us processing Your personal data for a particular purpose or purposes. Please note that the right to object only applies in certain circumstances and will depend on the purposes or legal basis for the processing.
7. **The right to data portability**. This only applies where You have provided personal data to Us directly, the legal basis for Us processing Your personal data is i) consent or ii) for the performance of a contract and We are processing Your data using automated means. In such instances You have the right to receive Your personal data (or request that We transfer it to another Controller) in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format.
8. **Rights relating to automated decision-making and profiling**. We do not use Your personal data in this way.
9. **The right to lodge a complaint** with any relevant Data Protection Authority, in particular in the Member State of Your residence, place of work or the place of processing Your personal data.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Data Subject Request** | **Timescale** |
| The right to be informed | When data is collected |
| The right of access | 2 weeks |
| The right to rectification | 2 weeks |
| The right to erasure | Without undue delay |
| The right to restrict processing | Without undue delay |
| The right to data portability | 2 weeks |
| The right to object | On receipt of the objection |
| Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling. | 2 weeks |

If You wish to exercise any of the aforementioned rights, please contact Us. We request that in the first instance You contact Our data protection officer at any time at [contact@slideplayer.com](mailto:contact@slideplayer.com).

### Your rights under california consumer privacy act

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.100 through 1798.104 grants you the following rights:

1. [to “opt out” of the “sale” of your “personal information” to “third parties”](https://slideplayer.com/support/ccpa/) (as those terms are defined in the CCPA).
2. to make requests to access categories and specific pieces of personal information about you collected by Us
3. to make requests to delete personal information about you.
4. to make requests to access categories and specific pieces of personal information sold to “third parties” for business purposes
5. to not be discriminated against on the basis of “opting out” of the sale of you personal information and exercising your other rights under CCPA

In order to make requests under CCPA, please visit [https://slideplayer.com/support/feedback/](https://slideplayer.com/support/feedback/) or write us at [contact@slideplayer.com](mailto:contact@slideplayer.com).

5\. Collection of Children’s PI
-------------------------------

Children can only use our services under the supervision of their parents/legal guardians and we always suggest minors (under the age of 16) not to submit any personal information to us or use the service. Consent for processing of minor’ PI shall be given by their holder of parental responsibility for the minor.

Personal Slideplayer.com does not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information or non-personally-identifiable information on the Slideplayer.com website from persons under 13 years of age, and no part of our website is directed to persons under 13. If you are under 13 years of age, then please do not use or access the Slideplayer.com website at any time or in any manner. If Slideplayer.com learns that personally identifiable information of persons less than 13 years of age has been collected on the Slideplayer.com website without verified parental consent, then Slideplayer.com will take the appropriate steps to delete this information.

6\. Cookies
-----------

When you visit the Slideplayer.com website, we may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. Slideplayer.com uses both session cookies and persistent cookies.

We show You the Cookie-banner for receiving of Your appropriate consent for usage of Cookies. You are able to restrict our usage of Cookies anytime in Your profile settings. It is impossible to maintain our web-site without minimal usage of Cookies and this is why we show You the Cookie-banner. We use required Cookies even if You do not accept banner.

We do not place our own cookies on your device. However, we work with Google. Google Adsense systems allow third-party cookies to be placed on your device. This Cookies used for personalized advertising with Google Adsense. Google’s use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve You ads based on Your prior visits to our website or other websites.

You may opt-out of personalized advertising by visiting Ads Settings [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/).

If You want to delete any cookies already stored on Your personal device or stop the cookies, You can do so by deleting Your existing cookies and/or altering Your browser's privacy settings. However, if, as mentioned above, due to Your personal device settings or browser settings, We are not able to use other technical solutions to store respective information, restriction/deletion of cookies may lead to your inability to access the content of Our Website.

7\. Usage of Personal Information
---------------------------------

Our privacy policy applies only to the Slideplayer.com website. Slideplayer.com contains links to other sites and file downloads from other sites. We do not exercise control over any site that may be linked to from within content on this site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such web sites.

We do not transfer Your Personal Data to third Parties, except cases, that are mentioned in this Privacy Policy. We work with other third-party companies, that help us to provide or improve our services, or use advertisements and related with it services. Thanks to this cooperation, we are able to work and to provide free of charge services around the world.

We transfer Your PI to third-party services Google Adsense and Google Analytics for maintaining Website functioning, for content personification, and for the showing of personalized advertisements.

If you submit personally identifiable information to us through the Slideplayer.com website, then we may use your personal information to operate, maintain, and provide features and functionality of the Slideplayer.com website.

Other information, that does not personally identify you as an individual is collected by Slideplayer.com from the site (such as, by way of example, patterns of use) and is exclusively owned by Slideplayer.com. Slideplayer.com can use this information in such a manner that Slideplayer.com, in its sole discretion, deems appropriate.

We may share specific aggregated, non-personal information with third parties, such as the number of users who have registered with us, the volume and pattern of traffic to and within the site, etc. That information will not identify you, the individual, in any way.

Any personal information or video and textual content that you voluntarily disclose online (on discussion boards, in messages and comments, within your public profile page, etc.) becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others. Your account name (not your email address) is displayed to other Users when you upload files or send messages through the Slideplayer.com website and other Users can contact you through messages and comments. Any content that you submit to the Slideplayer.com website may be viewed by the general public.

8.Public information
--------------------

Information voluntarily added in publicly visible parts of our Services, is considered to be public, even if it would otherwise be considered to be personally identifying or sensitive. We are empowered to disclose or transfer Your public information, such as information from Your user account, public releases \[publications\]. Remember, You are able to control the publicity of Your releases, publications, publicity of Your other information with help of privacy settings. Other information, such as Your name, nickname are always public.

When we transfer PI outside the European Union or EFTA, we ensure, that the adequate level of PI security is provided. During such transfer, we also ensure, that adequate level of Your rights protection is also applied, basing on adequacy analysis of the third country personal data protection legislation, basing on contractual obligations, assumed by the PI recipient.

If at any time in the future, we propose to use personal information for any purpose other than our internal use in maintaining the services, troubleshooting, improving our services, etc., then we will offer you an effective way to opt-out of the use of personal information for those other purposes.

We do not use your email address or other personally identifiable information to send commercial or marketing messages without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in or opt-out. We may, however, use your email address without further consent for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major Slideplayer.com site changes or for customer service purposes).

We restrict access to personal information to our employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop, or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution if they fail to meet these obligations.

You can control and manage PI, that is being provided to the Slideplayer.com via Your personal account by changing privacy settings anytime.

You may update or correct your personal profile information and email preferences at any time by visiting your account profile page. You can also close your account on the Slideplayer.com website. If you close your Slideplayer.com account, we will remove your name and other personally identifiable information from our publicly viewable data. We may retain certain data contributed by you if it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally-identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by applicable law. All retained data will continue to be subject to the terms of the Slideplayer.com Privacy Policy that you have previously agreed to. To request that we close your account and remove your information from the Slideplayer.com service, please send your request. Please send your request using an email account that you have registered with Slideplayer.com under your name.

When you send an email or other communication to us, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests, and improve our services. We won't share any information you send to us in those communications with any third parties.

We use cookies and log file information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit Slideplayer.com; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as a total number of visitors, pages viewed, etc.; and (e) track your entries, submissions, and status in promotions, sweepstakes, and contests.

9.Protection of the Personal Information
----------------------------------------

Slideplayer.com uses store and process Your PI on Slideplayer.coms servers in various jurisdictions, where our facilities and/or service providers are located. By filling a “consent application “You agree to this transfer, storing, or processing. Slideplayer.com will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that Your Personal Data is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy. Slideplayer.com protect Your Personal Data under internationally acknowledged standards, using physical, technical, and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, and alteration. Some of the safeguards Slideplayer.com use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access authorization controls. Slideplayer.com also authorize access to Personal Data only for those employees or contractors who require it to fulfill their job or service responsibilities. All of our physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards are designed to comply with applicable laws and regulations. Third parties may be located in other countries where the laws on processing of Personal Data may be less stringent than in Your country. From time to time, the Personal Data may be also stored in other locations, and in such cases, Slideplayer.com will ensure that the Personal Data will be stored and processed with the reasonable level of care and security.

We also point your attention to the fact that we are obliged to make back-ups. Therefore, Your PD is also kept in such back-ups with respect to all safety and legal requirements.

We store PD in logs during 3 weeks. We store Your PD in back-ups during 5 years. Moreover, Your PD are also stored in Google Analitycs during 50 months.

10\. Who do we share your personal data with?
---------------------------------------------

We do not share Your Personal Data to third Parties, except cases that are mentioned in this Privacy Policy.

1. **With Your consent**
    
    We will share information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Slideplayer.com when We have Your explicit consent.
    
2. **TO COMPLY WITH THE LAW**
    
    We may share information in response to a request for information if We believe disclosure is in accordance with, or required by, any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, including, but not limited to, meeting national security or law enforcement requirements. To the extent the law allows it, We will attempt to provide You with prior notice before disclosing Your information in response to such a request.
    
3. **IN AN EMERGENCY**
    
    We may share information if We believe that it's necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject (i.e. to prevent imminent serious physical harm or death to a person.)
    
4. **TO ENFORCE OUR POLICIES AND RIGHTS**
    
    We may share information if We believe Your actions are inconsistent with Our user agreements, rules, or other Slideplayer.com policies, or to protect the rights, property, and safety of ourselves and others.
    
5. **WITH OUR AFFILIATES**
    
    We may share information between and among Slideplayer.com and any of Our parents, affiliates, subsidiaries, and other companies under common control and ownership.
    
6. **WITH OUR PARTNERS**
    
    We may share information with vendors, consultants, and other service providers (but not with advertisers and ad partners) who need access to such information to carry out processing activities for us. The partner’s use of personal data will be subject to appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
    
    We engage service providers to perform functions and provide services to us. For example, We use third-party services like Google Analitycs
    
7. **WITH CCPA ACT**

11.Notification
---------------

**In the case of a personal data breach, Slideplayer.com shall without undue delay and, where feasible, not later than 72 hours after having become aware of it, notify the personal information breach to the supervisory competent authority,** unless the personal information breach is unlikely to result in a risk to the rights and freedoms of natural persons.

If Slideplayer.com learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. Slideplayer.com may post a notice on the Slideplayer.com website if a security breach occurs.

When the personal data breach is likely to result in a high risk to the rights and freedoms of users, the Slideplayer.com shall send warning emails (that have been previously provided) to users, PI of which may be exposed.

In the event that Slideplayer.com is acquired by or merged with a third-party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information we have collected from our Users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. If we become involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will notify Users before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used.

12\. Amendments to the Privacy Policy
-------------------------------------

Please note that this privacy policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this policy without your explicit consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice. To continue usage of the Slideplayer.com’s services, You will be asked to fill the consent application.

13\. Contact us
---------------

If you have any questions about this policy, please feel free to [contact us](https://slideplayer.com/support/feedback/) or to write to us at: [privacy@slideplayer.com](mailto:privacy@slideplayer.com)
